欢迎回来
Welcome back
到本节的最后一个编码挑战。
to the last coding challenge of this section.
和往常一样，我们将继续致力于我们的同一个项目。
And as always, we will keep working on our same project.
所以，这就是我们离开它的方式
So, this is how we left it
在我们的编码挑战之后，排名第二。
after our coding challenge, number two.
和往常一样，以此为出发点
And so as always, keep this as a starting point
希望你有一些 CodePen
which hopefully you have on some CodePen
或计算机上的某个位置。
or somewhere on your computer.
如果没有，此代码的链接将在本讲座中。
And if not, the link to this code will be in this lecture.
我想让你做什么
And what I want you to do
基本上就是把这个改成这个。
is basically to change this to this.
本质上只有两个大的变化。
And essentially there are only two big changes.
首先，我们这里有这个销售标签
First, we have this sale label here
在元素的左上角。
in this top left corner of the element.
然后也在这里，
And then also down here,
我们基本上有这六种可用的颜色
we have basically these six available colors
我们可以在其中购买鞋子。
in which we can buy the shoe.
所以我希望你在这里和这个地方建立这个部分。
So I want you to build this part here and this.
所以这次销售非常相似
So this sale is very similar
我们以前做过的事情。
to something that we did before.
所以希望你记得就是这样，好吧。
So hopefully you remember that's this, okay.
但是在这种情况下，您实际上不需要使用
But in this case, you actually don't need to use
一个伪元素。
a pseudo element for that.
您可以简单地添加一个元素，例如，
You can simply add a element, for example,
一段出售，然后放在这里，
a paragraph for the sale and then position it here,
就像我们在之前的一堂课中所做的那样。
just like we did it in one of the previous lectures.
现在，也许你注意到了这个细节
Now, maybe you're noticing this detail
在本文中，有一些空间
that in this text, there is some space
不同人物之间
between the different characters
还是这里的这些字母，对吧？
or these letters here, right?
所以有一个 CSS 属性可以让你做到这一点。
And so there is a CSS property which allows you to do that.
我想让你做的是谷歌。
And what I want you to do is to Google that.
所以我想让你用谷歌弄清楚
So I want you to use Google to figure out
你怎么能像我给你看的那样添加那个空间
how you can add that space a little bit like I showed you
在关于谷歌搜索的开发人员技能讲座中。
in the developer skills lecture about Googling.
所以现在你也可以应用它。
So now you can apply that as well.
好的？
Okay?
所以这是你需要做的事情之一。
So that is one of the things that you need to do.
另一个是这里。
And the other one is this here.
所以基本上你需要什么
So basically what you will need
要做的是创建一个元素。
to do is to create an element.
然后在那个元素里面，它可以是一个简单的 div。
And then inside of that element, which can be a simple div.
所以在那个元素里面，
So inside of that element,
那么你需要再创建六个元素。
then you need to create six more elements.
如果你愿意，这些也可以是 div。
And these can also be divs if you like.
然后你需要做的就是给他们每个人
And then all you need to do is to give each of them
一种颜色并将它们并排放置，
a color and put them side by side,
使用一个巧妙的小技巧
using a neat little trick
我们实际上也在其中一堂课中学到了这一点。
that we actually also learned in one of the lectures.
特别是讲座
And in particular, it was the lecture
如果我没记错的话，关于盒子的类型。
about the types of boxes, if I remember correctly.
所以这是我们在那里使用的一个不错的小技巧。
So this was a nice little trick that we used there.
所以你也可以在这里使用它。
And so you can use that here as well.
如果你不记得了，
And if you don't remember it,
一如既往绝对没有问题
as always there is absolutely no problem
如果您需要返回我们的代码
if you need to go back to our code
并查看我们是如何做到的。
and look up exactly how we did that.
当然，这里的这种技术也是如此。
And the same, of course, goes for this technique here.
所以我不指望你能记住
So I don't expect that you memorize
我在这里向您展示的所有技术。
all the techniques that I show you here.
但是，如果您可以在代码中查找它们
But if you can look them up in your code
并将它们转化为不同的情况，
and translate them to a different situation,
这已经是一项了不起的成就。
that already would be an amazing achievement.
好的。
Okay.
所以如果你能做到这一点，
So if you can just do that,
那么请继续暂停视频
then please go ahead and pause the video now
你完成后我会再见的。
and I'll see you once you're done.
好吧，回到这里工作。
All right back to work here.
让我们从销售标签开始。
And let's start with the sale label.
正如我所说，我将在某处简单地添加一个段落。
So as I said, I will simply add a paragraph somewhere.
既然我们会定位它，绝对，
And since we will position it, absolutely,
它在哪里并不重要。
it doesn't really matter where it is.
但我只是把它放在这里
But I will just put it here
接近价格和运费
close to the price and the shipping
因为从语义上讲，这就是
because semantically that's where
定位是有意义的。
it makes sense to be located.
所以让我们给它一个销售类。
So let's give it a class of sale.
然后我们也想要销售文本。
And then we want the text of sale as well.
然后让我们关闭它。
And then let's close this.
现在我们在我们的 CSS 中。
And now we're here in our CSS.
让我们把它也靠近这个航运。
Let's put it also close to this shipping.
所以下来这里。
So down here.
让我们从添加一些视觉样式开始。
And let's start by adding some visual styles to it.
例如，一些背景颜色。
So some background color, for example.
在这里你可以使用
And here you could have just used
你想要的任何红色。
any red color that you wanted.
例如，使用 VS Code 颜色选择器。
For example, using the VS Code Color Picker.
我也这样做了。
And I also did that.
所以我想出的颜色是ec2f2f。
And so the color I came up with is ec2f2f.
像这样。
Just like this.
它实际上去那里。
It actually go there.
现在，对。
Now, right.
然后让我们担心文本。
Then let's worry about the text.
所以让我们把它变成白色。
So let's make it white.
像这样。
Like this.
给它一个 12 像素的字体大小并使其大写。
Give it a font size of 12 pixels and make it uppercase.
并使其大胆。
And make it bold as well.
所以字体粗细，粗体。
So font weight, bold.
让我们给它一些填充。
Let's give it some padding.
顶部 7 个像素，左右 15 个像素。
7 pixels at the top, 15 left and right.
再说一次，这些并不重要。
And again, these don't really matter.
但很多时候这是个好主意
But many times it's a good idea
有水平填充
to have the horizontal padding
是一种垂直的两倍。
to be kind of double of vertical.
这是一个很好的经验法则
That's a good rule of thumb
很多时候看起来非常好。
that many times looks very good.
现在下一步是，实际上我们想要这个元素
And now the next step is that, actually we want this element
只是为了占据它实际需要的空间。
only to occupy the space that it actually needs.
因此，有两种技术。
So, there are two techniques for that.
嗯，实际上只有一个，但你也可以善良
Well, actually just one, but you could also kind
以不同的方式实现这一目标。
of achieve this in a different way.
所以最好的方法是做到这一点
So the best way to do this
将显示设置为内联框，
would be to set a display to inline box,
实际上是内联块。
actually inline block.
所以现在确实，就像任何内联元素一样，
And so now indeed, just like any inline element,
盒子只占据其内容的空间。
the box only occupies the space of its content.
好的。
Okay.
所以这是正确的解决方案，
So this is the correct solution,
但是让我们对此进行评论以向您展示另一种解决方案。
but let's comment this out to show you another solution.
所以你可能也猜到了
So you could have also kind of guessed
这个元素的 with，如果你想的话。
the with of this element, if you wanted.
假设 100 像素，然后我们可以调整它。
Let's say 100 pixels and then we could adjust it.
因此，假设只有 80 像素或 50 像素。
So let's say just 80 pixels or just 50 pixels maybe.
甚至40个。
Or 40 even.
然后一旦你接近了，
And then once you kind of got close,
然后你可以只说文本、对齐、居中。
you can then just say text, align, center.
因为现在实际上有足够的空间
Because now there is actually enough space
围绕里面的元素
around the element inside
然后可以将其中的文本居中。
of which the text could then be centered.
好的。
Okay.
所以当我们实际上有一个宽度时，
So when we have actually a width,
那么我们就不再是那种情况了
then we are no longer in that situation
其中文本对齐中心在元素中没有意义。
where text align center doesn't make sense in an element.
就像我们之前在这里使用这些链接一样。
Like we had before here with these links.
还记得吗？所以我觉得就像两堂课前一样。
Remember that? So I think like two lectures ago.
但无论如何，这不是首选的解决方案，
But anyway, this is not the preferred solution,
但我们也可以这样做。
but it is something that we could also have done.
因此，我发现向您展示这一点也很有趣。
So, I found that interesting to also show you that.
所以现在是时候真正
And so now it's time to actually
绝对将这个元素放在这里。
absolutely position this element right here.
所以让我们记住我们需要做的第一件事
So let's remember that the first thing that we need to do
为了绝对定位一个元素
in order to absolutely position an element
是定义相对于什么父元素，
is to define in relation to what parent element,
这个元素应该被定位。
this element should be positioned.
等等那个父元素，我们将位置设置为相对。
And so on that parent element, we set position to relative.
所以在这种情况下，这应该很容易，对吧？
So in this case, that should be quite easy, right?
这就是这里的产品。
That is simply this product here.
所以这篇文章同类产品。
So this article with the class of product.
所以，这就是我们现在想要的地方
And so, this is where now we want
将位置设置为相对。
to set position to relative.
所以，现在我们可以回到这里
And so, now we can go back here
并说绝对位置。
and say position absolute.
并将顶部和左侧设置为零。只是为了开始。
And set the top and left to zero. Just to get started.
好的。
Okay.
现在我们可以猜测值
And now we can kind of guess the values
这应该在哪里。
where this should be.
所以，假设是负 15 像素。
So, let's say like minus 15 pixels.
这可以多一点，17。
That can be a little bit more, 17.
是的。
Yeah.
所以现在它就像在中间
So now it's like nicely in the middle
现在让我们将它也向左移动 30 个像素。
and now let's move it also like 30 pixels to the left.
所以这还不是很集中。
So that's not quite centered yet.
比如说35。
Let's say 35.
好吧，让我们把它设为 34，
Well, let's actually make it 34,
所以它正好是顶部的两倍。
so it's exactly double off the top.
好的。有了这个，我们几乎完成了这部分。
All right. So with this, we are almost done with this part.
所缺少的只是这个额外的空间
All that's missing is this extra space
人物之间。
between the characters.
对？
Right?
所以要给它额外的触感，
So to give it this extra touch,
也因为我想要你
and also because I wanted you
练习你的谷歌搜索技能。
to practice your Googling skills.
所以我会用谷歌搜索的是，
So what I would have Googled is,
CSS 在字符之间添加空格，
CSS add space between characters,
或者你也可以写信，
or you could have written letters as well,
但在这里你实际上立即得到结果。
but here you actually immediately get the result.
所以字母间距。
So letters spacing.
但我对这里更感兴趣，
But I'm more interested in here,
通常在堆栈溢出回复中
usually in a stack overflow reply
或 MDN 的这个文档。
or this documentation of MDN.
所以这里我们有字母间距，
So here we have letter spacing,
这看起来像我们想要的东西。
which looks like something we want.
所以在这里，我们确实像往常一样
And so here, indeed we get as always
几个不同的例子。
a couple of different examples.
所以，是的。这是我们要使用的属性。
And so, yeah. This is the property that we're gonna use.
所以我在复制它。
So I'm copying it.
让我们把它放在这里，接近这些风格。
Let's put it here, close to these styles.
我将它设置为两个像素。
And I'm setting it to two pixels.
是的。这实际上看起来好多了。
And yeah. That actually looks a lot nicer.
现在我们只需要喜欢，推送它
Now we just need to like, push it
甚至在那边多一点，像这样。
even a bit more to the side there, like this.
将其居中。是的，就是这样。
To center it. And yeah, that's it.
所以我们完成了这部分。
So we are done with this part.
所以现在让我们在这里快速添加这些颜色。
So now let's quickly add those colors here.
正如我之前所说，我们基本上会创建一个 div。
And as I said, previously, we will basically create a div.
所以一个没有任何语义意义的容器。
So a container without any semantic meaning.
然后在那里，我将再创建六个 div。
And then in there, I will create six more divs.
然后他们每个人都会得到自己的背景颜色。
And then each of them will get its own background color.
所以，这应该在链接之后。
So, that should be right here after the link.
对？因此，在链接之后和这些产品详细信息之前。
Right? So after the link and before these product details.
所以一个div，我称之为颜色。
So a div, and I'm calling it the colors.
让我们立即关闭它，这样我们就不会忘记它。
Let's just immediately close it so we don't forget it.
因为这个编辑器不如 VS Code。
Because this editor is not as good as VS Code.
但是还是很有帮助的
But it's still quite helpful
实际使用 CodePen 来完成类似的事情。
to actually use CodePen for something like this.
现在我们将在这里创建另一个 div。
And now we will just create another div in here.
颜色。
Color.
然后实际上这并没有有任何内容。
And then actually this doesn't have any content at all.
好的。
All right.
所以这是我们以前没有真正做过的事情。
So this is something we didn't really do before.
所以让我解释一下，告诉你我们将如何做到这一点。
And so let me just explain and show you how we will do it.
所以我们想要六种颜色。
So we want six colors.
所以我只是复制粘贴它六次。
So I'm just a copy pasting it six times.
是的。
So yeah.
让我们把它放在最后。
Let's put that right here at the end.
所以就像在 HTML 中一样。
So just like in the HTML.
所以颜色类并不是很重要，我认为。
So the colors class is not really important, I think.
因此，让我们从定义每个正方形开始。
So let's just start by defining each of the squares.
所以每一个。
So each of these.
所以基本上我们把它们做成一个正方形
So basically we make them a square
通过给他们一定的高度，然后给他们一个宽度
by giving them a certain height and then a width
这是一样的。
which is the same.
所以让我给你看。
So let me show that to you.
我们应该做的第一件事是
The first thing we should do is
给他们一个背景颜色
to give them a background color
以便更容易看到它。
to make it easier to see it.
第一个我认为是黑色的。
The first one I think was black.
好的。
All right.
但现在它们不可见
But right now they are not visible
因为他们没有任何内容。
because they don't have any content.
但是如果我们给它们一个高度和宽度，
But if we give them a height and the width,
然后它们将变得可见。
then they will become visible.
所以让我们这样做。高度 22 像素。
So let's do that. Height 22 pixels.
所以现在他们马上就长高了
And so now immediately they get a height
然后他们占据了他们可以占据的所有空间
and then they occupy all the space that they can
因为默认情况下它们是块级元素，对吗？
because they are block level elements by default, right?
所以它们是 div，因此
So they are divs and therefore
默认情况下是块级别。
that is by default a block level.
但是现在如果我们指定它们的宽度相同，
But now if we specify their width to be the same,
所以它看起来像一个正方形，
so it looks like a square then,
那么当然他们不再这样做了。
Well then of course they no longer do that.
好的。
Okay.
所以当然我们离最终的结果还很远。
So of course we are still far away from the final result.
但为了有效地继续，
But in order to continue effectively,
现在让我们给他们每个人一个不同的颜色。
let's now give each of them a different color.
那么我们该怎么做呢？
So how can we do that?
好吧，我实际上会为他们每个人添加另一个类。
Well, I will actually add another class to each of them.
这是完全可能的。
And that is completely possible.
请记住，我们被允许
Remember that we are allowed
给每个元素一个以上的类。
to give each element more than one class.
所以我之前给你看了。
So I showed you that before.
所以我们这样做的方式是添加一个空格
So the way we do that, is to add a space
然后简单地添加另一个。
and then simply add another one.
所以第一个是黑色的，
So the first one was black,
然后是蓝色、红色、黄色、绿色和棕色。
then blue, red, yellow, green, and brown.
所以，
And so,
好吧，在第一个中，我们实际上不需要这样做
Well, in the first one, we actually don't need to do that
因为它们已经是黑色的了，所有的。
because they are black already, all of them.
所以我们基本上可以覆盖它
And so we can then basically override that
在所有其他的。
in all the other ones.
所以我们称它为蓝色。
So let's call this one, the color blue.
然后让我复制粘贴几次。
And then let me just copy-paste that a couple of times.
这么红，
So red,
黄色的，
yellow,
绿色，
green,
和
and
棕色的。
brown.
现在我们当然会有
And now we will of course have
在这里选择所有这些。
to select all of them right here.
再说一次，你本可以上来的
So again, you could have come up
任何你喜欢的蓝色。
with any blue color that you like.
我的选择是这个，2f6ee2。
My choice was this one, 2f6ee2.
那么让我们看看。
So let's see.
事实上，现在它是蓝色的。
And indeed, now it is blue.
现在，我们将复制几次。
Now, we'll just copy this a couple of times.
好的。
Okay.
这么红，
So red,
黄色的，
yellow,
绿色，
green,
和棕色。
and brown.
所以不是在这里，而是在这里。
So not here, but here.
实际上，这里让我们使用我以前的红色。
Here let's use the same red that I had before, actually.
然后黄色是 f0ef1e。
And then the yellow was f0ef1e.
绿色是 90cc20。
Green is 90cc20.
最后棕色是 885214。
And finally the brown is 885214.
你去吧。
And there you go.
我们有六种不同的颜色。
There we have all six different colors.
现在，我们需要做的就是将它们并排放置。
Now, all we need to do is to put them side by side.
那么我们该怎么做呢？
So how can we do that?
嗯，我们之前学过一个巧妙的技巧，
Well, there is a neat trick that we learned before,
也就是改变显示属性
which is to change the display property
这些元素的内联块。
of these elements to inline block.
所以我们现在将设置所有这六个元素。
So we will now set all of these six elements.
所以所有这些都有颜色类
So all of them, which have the class of color
到内联块。
to inline block.
因为这样，他们只会占据空间
Because like this, they will only occupy the space
他们需要，他们也会
that they need and they will also
不要在它们之后创建任何换行符。
not create any line breaks after them.
这正是我们想要的。
And so that is exactly what we want.
现在我们不能使用 inline 因为
Now we could not use inline because
那么高度和宽度将无法按预期工作。
then the height and width wouldn't really work as expected.
或者至少他们不应该。
Or at least they shouldn't.
你会发现它确实行不通。
And you see that indeed it doesn't work.
所以它需要是内联块
So it needs to be inline block
因为记住高度和宽度，
because remember height and width,
不适用于内联元素。
do not apply to inline elements.
现在我们需要的只是一点点余地
And now all we need is a small margin
在他们每个人的右边
to the right of each of them
比方说，12 像素。
of let's say, 12 pixels.
我们开始了。
And there we go.
可能有点过分了吧所以10像素。
It's a bit too much, maybe. So 10 pixels.
就是这样。
And that's it.
这就是我们需要做的。
So that's all we need to do.
好吧，实际上我们失踪了
Well, actually we are missing
就像这个锚之后的一些空间。
like some space here after this anchor.
记住我们实际上是如何
And remember how we actually
之前已经有这个问题了。
already had this problem before.
所以我们试图增加一些空间。
So we tried to add some space.
所以这个锚点有一些边距底部，但它没有用。
So some margin bottom to this anchor, but it didn't work.
所以解决方法是添加那个空间
And so the work around was to then add that space
在这个标题的顶部。
at the top of this heading.
还记得吗？
Remember that?
所以这就是为什么这里的这些细节标题，有边缘顶部。
So that's why here these details title, has the margin top.
当我们不明白的时候
And by the time we didn't understand
为什么向此锚元素添加边距底部不起作用。
why adding margin bottom to this anchor element didn't work.
但现在我们确实做到了。
But now we actually do.
所以让我们也这样做。
So let's do that as well.
所以就在这里。
So that's right here.
所以让我们在这里添加一个 30 像素的边距底部，
So let's add a margin bottom here of 30 pixels,
这仍然行不通。
which will still not work.
但同样，我们现在知道为什么它不起作用了。
But again, we now know why it doesn't work.
原因是，
And the reason is that,
锚元素是一个内联元素。
the anchor element is an inline element.
在内联元素上，
And on inline elements,
顶部和边距底部不适用。
the top and margin bottoms do not apply.
所以，为了再次解决这个问题，
So, to fix that once again,
我们需要将其显示为内联块。
we need to display this as an inline block.
所以，很容易。
So, easy enough.
显示内联块，
Display inline block,
你去吧。
and there you go.
我们有，我们的 30 像素现在很好地显示了。
There we have, our 30 pixels now nicely displayed.
好的。
Okay.
我认为，
And I think with this,
我们的解决方案看起来与我们的演示完全相同。
our solution looks exactly the same as our demo.
所以我们现在已经完成了。
So we are done now as it looks.
是的。所以，看起来是这样。
Yep. So, it seems so.
所以，是的。
And so, yeah.
这实际上是对 CSS 部分的介绍的总结。
That's actually a wraps up this introduction to CSS section.
再来一次，恭喜
So one more time, congratulations
达到课程的第一部分。
for reaching this first part of the course.
现在你已经掌握了 HTML 和 CSS 的所有基础知识
And you now have all the fundamentals of HTML and CSS
开始构建布局所需的。
that you need in order to start building layouts.
这实际上是 CSS 的主要部分之一。
Which is actually one of the main parts of CSS.
所以有一整节 w对此很感兴趣。
So there's a whole section waiting about that.
所以一旦你完成了所有的审查
And so once you're done reviewing everything
我们在这里做的，我会在下一节见到你。
that we did here, I will see you in that next section.
一旦你准备好了。
Once you are ready.